Preliminary Inventory of the Maria Angels Solé Collection, 1943-1985
Hoover Institution Archives
Maria Angels Solé Collection,
1943-1985
91048
Solé, Maria Angels
18 manuscript boxes 7.5 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Serial issues, pamphlets, leaflets, flyers, internal bulletins, and conference proceedings, issued by Spanish socialist, communist, anarchist, Trotskyist, Maoist and trade-union organizations, and by Catalan and Basque nationalist organizations, relating to conditions in Spain under the regime of Generalissimo Francisco Franco, to prospects for its downfall, and to conditions in the immediate post-Franco period. Most issuances were published or distributed clandestinely.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1991.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Spain--Politics and government--1939-1975.; Spain--Politics and government--1975-; Socialism--Spain.; Communism--Spain.; Anarchism--Spain.; Fourth International.; Trade-unions--Spain.; Labor movement--Spain.; Catalans--Spain.; Basques--Spain.; Nationalism--Catalonia (Spain); Nationalism--Euzkadi (Spain); Spain--Minorities.; Communism.; Spain.
Container List
- Socialist parties (various), 1943-1983 (Box 1)
- Union General de Trabajadores, 1958-1978
- Confederacion Nacional del Trabajo, 1965-1979 (Box 2)
- Comisiones Obreras, 1968-1982 (Box 3)
- Comisiones Obreras, 1968-1982 (Box 4)
- Partido Comunista de Espana, 1970-1979
- Partido Comunista de Espana, 1970-1979 (Box 5)
- Partido Socialista Unificado de Cataluna, 1944-1984 (Box 6)
- Partido Socialista Unificado de Cataluna, 1944-1984 (Box 7)
- Partido Comunista de Espana (Internacional)/Partido del Trabajo de Espana, 1969-1978
- Partido Comunista de Espana (Internacional)/Partido del Trabajo de Espana, 1969-1978 (Box 8)
- Organizacion Comunista de Espana (Bandera Roja), 1968-1978
- Organizacion Comunista de Espana (Bandera Roja), 1968-1978 (Box 9)
- Organizacion Revolucionaria de Trabajadores, 1974-1979
- Movimiento Comunista de Espana, 1973-1980 (Box 10)
- Organizacion de Izquierda Comunista de Espana, 1972-1978
- Partido Comunista de Espana (Internacionalista), 1969-1971 (Box 11)
- Partido Comunista de Espana (Internacional-Linea Proletaria), 1974-1979
- Partido Comunista de Espana (Marxista-Leninista), 1967-1977
- Union Comunista de Liberacion, 1972-1977
- Cuadernos Rojos, 1971-1974 (Box 12)
- Organizacion Comunista (Lucha de Clases), 1971-1972
- Accion Comunista, 1967-1976
- Partido Obrero de Unificacion Marxista, 1964-1976
- Unificacion Comunista, 1973-1985
- Grupo Comunista Revolucionario, 1974-1976
- Partido Comunista de Unificacion, 1976
- Organizacion Comunista, 1975
- Insurreccion, 1975
- Germania Socialista, 1976
- Organizacion Independencia Proletaria, 1976
- Partido Comunista de Espana (Reconstituido), n.d.
- Fraccion Bolchevique-Leninista, 1973-1974
- Liga Comunista Revolucionaria, 1970-1983 (Box 13)
- Liga Comunista, 1973-1979 (Box 14)
- Organizacion Troskista/Partido Obrero Revolucionario de Espana, 1972-1982
- Organizacion Troskista/Partido Obrero Revolucionario de Espana, 1972-1982 (Box 15)
- Partido Obrero Revolucionario-Trosquista, 1968-1971
- Liga Spartaquista, 1977-1983
- Liga Obrera Comunista, 1976-1980
- Organizacion Comunista Internacional, 1977
- Tendencia Cuartainternacionalista, 1982
- Convergencia Democratica de Catalunya, 1976-1979 (Box 16)
- Front Nacional de Catalunya, 1956-1975
- Partit Socialista d'Alliberament Nacional, 1970-1978
- Partit Socialista d'Alliberament Nacional (Provisionals), 1975-1979
- Partit Popular de Catalunya, 1973-1974
- Esquerra Republicana de Catalunya, 1945-1983
- Unio Democratica de Catalunya, 1964-1977
- Nacionalistes d'Esquerra, 1984
- Comissio Coordinador de Forces Politiques de Catalunya, 1970-1974 (Box 17)
- Assemblea de Catalunya, 1972-1978
- Independent (non-party) Catalan publications, 1962-1979
- Independent (non-party) publications, 1969-1980 (Box 18)
- Student movement publications, 1963-1977
- Basque nationalist publications, 1970-1978
Material Cataloged Separately
The serials listed below have been withdrawn from the Maria Angels Solé Collection in the Hoover Institution Archives and have been cataloged individually in the Hoover Institution Library
Confederacion Nacional del Trabajo publications:
C.N.T., 1947-1978
Solidaridad Obrera, 1945-1978
Ruta, 1950-1953
Tierra y Libertad, 1964-1979
Despertar, 1961
Espana Libre, 1955-1961
Cenit, 1954-1980
Umbral, 1962-1969
Frente Libertario, 1970-1977
Partido Comunista de Espana publications:
Mundo Obrero, 1968-1978
Nuestra Bandera, 1968-1976
Partido Socialista Unificado de Cataluna publication: Treball, 1971-1982
Liga Comunista Revolucionaria publication: Combate, 1971-1982
Organizacion Troskista/Partido Obrero Revolucionario de Espana publication: La Aurora, 1972-1980